pushalert.co 2019-04-12

# PushAlert Privacy Policy - PushAlert

_This PushAlert Privacy Policy ( **"Policy"** ) outlines the information that InkWired Technologies Private Limited ( **"PushAlert"** , **"we"** , **"us"** or **"our"** ) gathers, how we use that information, and the options you have to access, correct, or delete such information._

### PushAlert's Promise

Our mission to help make the internet more accessible, secure and transparent is rooted in the importance we place on establishing trust with our Customers, Website Visitors, and the Internet community. To earn and maintain that trust, we commit to communicating transparently, providing security, and protecting the privacy of data on our systems.

We keep your personal information personal and private. We will not sell, rent, share, or otherwise disclose your personal information to anyone except as necessary to provide our services or as otherwise described in this Policy without first providing you with notice and the opportunity to consent. 

### 1\. Policy Application:

This Policy applies to PushAlert’s collection, use, and disclosure of the information of the following categories of individuals: 

  * **Attendees:** Individuals who provide their information to PushAlert or PushAlert representatives when they attend or register to attend PushAlert-sponsored events or other events at which PushAlert participates.
  * **Website Visitors:** Individuals who visit our Websites and who may opt to provide an email address to receive communications from PushAlert. For the purposes of this Policy, "Websites" shall refer collectively to PushAlert.co as well as any other websites PushAlert owns and that link to this Policy. For clarity, "Websites" does not include any sites owned or operated by our Customers. 
  * **Customers:** Those who register on their own or on behalf of an entity or organization to use any of the PushAlert Services (as defined below), including administrators on a Customer account. For the purposes of this Policy, "Services" shall refer to all cloud services marketed for subscription at PushAlert.co, including when Services are sold by an authorized partner or reseller.
  * **End Users:** Individuals who visit our Customers’ websites and opt-into receiving web push notifications and whose information we process in order to provide the Services to our Customers pursuant to our agreements with them. 

This Policy does not apply to our Customers’ websites, which may have their own terms and privacy policies. Our Customers are solely responsible for establishing policies for and ensuring compliance with all applicable laws and regulations, including those relating to the collection of personal information in connection with the use of our Services by End Users with whom our Customers interact.

PushAlert’s Websites and Services are not intended for, nor designed to attract, individuals under the age of sixteen. PushAlert does not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from any person under the age of sixteen (16). If any parent or guardian comes to the knowledge that data has been shared by a child under the age of sixteen (16), they can reach out to us directly to get the data removed from our systems. 

### 2\. Information We Collect

**Attendees**

  * We may ask for and collect personal information such as your name, address, phone number and email address when you register for or attend a sponsored event or other events at which PushAlert (and/or its representatives) participates. 

**Website Visitors**

  * **Name, email address, and other contact information**. We ask for and—at your option—collect personal information from you when you submit web forms on our Websites, including opportunities to sign up for and agree to receive email communications from us. We also may ask you to submit such personal information if you choose to use interactive features of the Websites, including participation in surveys, contests, promotions, sweepstakes, requesting customer support, or otherwise communicating with us. We will send such communications in accordance with applicable law.
  * **Log Files**. Just as when you visit and interact with most websites and services delivered via the Internet, when you visit our Websites, including the PushAlert Support Ticketing System, we gather certain information and store it in log files. This information may include but is not limited to anonymized Internet Protocol (IP) addresses (last octet removed), system configuration information, URLs of referring pages, and locale and language preferences.
  * **Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies**. We may use cookies and other information gathering technologies for a variety of purposes, such as providing us with information about how you interact with our Websites and assisting us in our marketing efforts. You can control how websites use cookies by configuring your browser's privacy settings (please refer to your browser's help function to learn more about cookie controls). Note that if you disable cookies entirely, PushAlert’s Websites may not function properly. We may also use cookies and similar technologies to provide you advertising on third-party sites based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish not to have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt-out by clicking here (or if located in the European Union, click here). For more information about the cookies PushAlert uses, please see our [Cookie Policy](https://pushalert.co/cookie-policy.html).
  * **Interactive Areas**. The Websites may offer publicly accessible blogs, community forums, comments sections, discussion forums, or other interactive features ("Interactive Areas"). If you choose to participate in any of these Interactive Areas, please be aware that that any information that you post in an Interactive Area might be read, collected, and used by others who access it. If you wish to remove your personal information from any of our Interactive Areas, please see the section below entitled, Your Data Rights.

**Customers:**

  * **Customer Account Information**. When you register for a PushAlert account, we collect your email address. We will also ask you to enter your website domain in order to participate in the Services. We refer to this information as "Customer Account Information" for the purposes of this Policy. Customer Account Information is required to identify you as a Customer and permit you to access your account(s). By voluntarily providing us with such Customer Account Information, you represent that you are the owner of such personal data or otherwise have the requisite consent to provide it to us.
  * **Payment Information**. You are not required to enter your credit card information unless and until you decide to continue with a paid subscription to our Services. When you sign up for one of our paid Services, you must provide billing information. The information you will need to submit depends on which billing method you choose. For example, if you pay with a credit card, we will collect your billing address and our PCI DSS compliant payment processors ("Payment Processors") keep the credit card on record, we at PushAlert do not store credit card numbers or personal account numbers.

**End Users:**

  * PushAlert provides web push notification services that our Customers use to engage with end users of their website. Web Push is based on informed consent and no data is collected from end-users without them first opting into web push notifications on their browsers. The next points relate to data collection, only after consent is provided.
  * We collect End Users’ information when they use our Customers’ websites, web applications, and APIs. This information may include but is not limited to anonymized IP addresses (last octet removed), location, system configuration information, and URLs of Customer’s website accessed by end user (collectively, "Log Data"). We collect and use Log Data to operate, maintain, and improve our Services in performance of our obligations under our Customer agreements.
  * For ecommerce automation we may also collect cart and order information including but not limited to cart identifier, order identifier, customer name. This data is only collected if our ecommerce marketing features or APIs are enabled. This data is used to provide order and product updates to end users to which they have subscribed to. It is our Customers who are responsible for establishing policies for and ensuring compliance with all applicable laws and regulations including those relating to the collection of personal information from their end-users to enable and use these features.
  * Cookies. We use functional cookies and browser local storage to keep track of end-user subscription and these are only created after interacting with web push opt-in. These functional cookies and browser local storage data are not shared with any third-party and do not contain any personal information. No third-party cookies are stored on end-user devices. You can control how websites use cookies by configuring your browser's privacy settings (please refer to your browser's help function to learn more about cookie controls). Note that if you disable cookies entirely, we will not be able to provide you with the Service, as intended. For more information about the cookies PushAlert uses, please see our [Cookie Policy](https://pushalert.co/cookie-policy.html).

### Legal Basis for Processing (EEA only)

If you are an individual from the European Economic Area (EEA), please note that our legal basis for collecting and using your personal information will depend on the personal information collected and the specific context in which we collect it. We normally will collect personal information from you only where: (a) we have your consent to do so, (b) where we need your personal information to perform a contract with you (e.g. to deliver the PushAlert Services you have requested), or (c) where the processing is in our legitimate interests. Please note that in most cases, if you do not provide the requested information, PushAlert will not be able to provide the requested service to you.

In some cases, we may also have a legal obligation to collect personal information from you, or may otherwise need the personal information to protect your vital interests or those of another person.

Where we rely on your consent to process your personal data, you have the right to withdraw or decline consent at any time. Where we rely on our legitimate interests to process your personal data, you have the right to object.

If you have any questions about or need further information concerning the legal basis on which we collect and use your personal information, please contact us at [support@pushalert.co](mailto:support@pushalert.co).

### 3\. How We Use Information We Collect

PushAlert only processes personal information in a way that is compatible with and relevant for the purpose for which it was collected or authorized. As a general matter, for all categories of data we collect except End User data, we may use the information we collect (including personal information, to the extent applicable) to:

    * provide, operate, maintain, improve, and promote the Website and Services; enable you to access and use the Website and Services; process and complete transactions, and send you related information, including purchase confirmations and invoices;
    * send transactional messages, including responses to your comments, questions, and requests; provide customer service and support; and send you technical notices, updates, security alerts, and support and administrative messages;
    * send commercial communications, in accordance with your communication preferences, such as providing you with information about products and services, features, surveys, newsletters, offers, promotions, contests, and events about us and our partners; and send other news or information about us and our partners. See Section 10 below for information on managing your communication preferences.
    * monitor and analyze trends, usage, and activities in connection with the Websites and Services and for marketing or advertising purposes;
    * comply with legal obligations as well as to investigate and prevent fraudulent transactions, unauthorized access to the Services, and other illegal activities;
    * personalize the Websites and Services, including by providing features or content that match your interests and preferences; and
    * process for other purposes for which we obtain your consent.

**Information from Third Party Services**

We may combine information we collect as described above with personal information we obtain from third parties. For example, we may combine information entered on a PushAlert sales submission form with information we receive from a third-party sales intelligence platform vendor to enhance our ability to market our Services to Customers or potential Customers.

**End Users**

We do not sell, rent, share, or otherwise disclose our Customers’ End User data to any third party. Nor is the End User data used for any marketing purpose by PushAlert. We may use the information we collect from End Users (including personal information, to the extent applicable) to:

    * provide, operate, maintain, and improve the Website and Services;
    * enable you to access and use the Website and Services;
    * process for other purposes for which we obtain your consent.

### 4\. Information Sharing

We work with other companies who help us run our business ("Service Providers"). These companies provide services to help us deliver customer support, process credit card payments, manage and contact our existing Customers as well as sales leads, provide marketing support, and otherwise operate and improve our Services. These Service Providers may only process personal information pursuant to our instructions and in compliance both with this Privacy Policy and other applicable confidentiality and security measures and regulations.

Specifically, we do not permit our Service Providers to use any personal information we share with them for their own marketing purposes or for any other purpose than in connection with the services they provide to us. Your end-user data is not shared with any Service Provider.

In addition to sharing with Service Providers as described above, we may also share your information with others in the following circumstances:

    * With our resellers and other sales partners who may help us distribute the Services to Customers;
    * In the event of a merger, sale, change in control, or reorganization of all our part of our business;
    * When we are required to disclose personal information to respond to subpoenas, court orders, or legal process, or to establish or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims.
    * Where we have a good-faith belief sharing is necessary to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of our Service Agreement, or as otherwise required to comply with our legal obligations; or
    * as you may otherwise consent from time to time.

We do not sell, rent, or share personal information with third parties for their direct marketing purposes.

### 5\. Data Aggregation

PushAlert may aggregate data we acquire about our Customers and their End Users, including the Log Data described above. For example, we may assemble data to determine traffic patterns on a website to compile statistics and help with usage analytics. Such non-personally identifiable, aggregated data is also not shared with any third-party.

### 6\. International Information Transfers

PushAlert is an India-based, global company. We primarily store your information in the United States. To facilitate our global operations, we may transfer and access such information from around the world, including from other countries in which PushAlert has operations for the purposes described in this Policy.

If you are accessing or using our Websites or Services or otherwise providing information to us, you are agreeing to the transfer of your personal information to the United States and other jurisdictions in which we operate.

### 7\. Data Subject Rights

**Attendees, Website Visitors, and Customers** : You have the right to access, correct, update, export, or delete your personal information. You may email us at support@pushalert.co with any such subject access requests ("SAR"), and we will respond within thirty (30) days. Customers also can access, correct, export, or update their Account Information by editing their profile or organization record at PushAlert.co.

**End Users** : You have the right to access, correct, update, export, or delete your personal information. You can delete your information stored with us by unsubscribing from notifications by following the instructions [here](https://pushalert.co/documentation/delete-your-data). PushAlert automatically removes expired endpoints and associated data. You may also email us at support@pushalert.co with any such subject access requests ("SAR") with your Subscription Key ([How to get subscription key?](https://pushalert.co/documentation/extract-subscription-key)), and we will respond within thirty (30) days. In case our Customers receive a SAR from an end-user regarding our service, PushAlert will unequivocally comply with the request.

For any SAR, we will need to verify a requestor is inquiring about their own information before we can assist. Where a SAR may implicate the personal data of another individual, we must balance the request against the risk of violating another person’s privacy rights. We will comply with SARs to the extent required by applicable law. In the EU, you also have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority.

### 8\. Data Portability

We strive for data portability. You can export all the endpoints and associated data required for web push and move to a different service pursuant to the conditions mentioned below. If you require data portability please make sure you use your own FCM/GCM configuration, while registering for PushAlert or while adding a new website to your PushAlert account and also use your own HTTPS domain/subdomain.

**Technical Limitations:**

If you use HTTP integration method then the subscriptions are bound to a PushAlert subdomain, so you cannot move this subscription data to a different service due to technical limitations. Similarly, if you use the HTTPS method of integration but do not use your own FCM/GCM configuration, your subscriptions will be tied to PushAlert, and you cannot move this subscription data to a different service. Additional technical limitations apply to Safari desktop and to legacy products.

You can request for a data export by reaching out to [support@pushalert.co](mailto:support@pushalert.co).

### 9\. Data Retention

We retain your personal information to provide services to you and as otherwise necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. We will retain your personal information for no more 90 days following the date on which you terminate your use of the Services, unless we are otherwise required by law or regulation to retain your personal information for longer.

### 10\. Communication Preferences

You may manage your receipt of commercial communications by clicking on the "unsubscribe" link located on the bottom of such emails, through your account settings if you have a PushAlert account, or you may send a request to [support@pushalert.co](mailto:support@pushalert.co).

### 11\. Data Security, Data Integrity

We take all reasonable steps to protect information we receive from you from loss, misuse or unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and/or destruction. We have put in place appropriate physical, technical, and administrative measures to safeguard and secure your information, and we make use of privacy-enhancing technologies such as encryption. If you have any questions about the security of your personal information, you can contact us at [support@pushalert.co](mailto:support@pushalert.co).

### 12\. Notification Of Changes

If we make changes to this Policy that we believe materially impact the privacy of your personal data, we will promptly provide notice of any such changes (and, where necessary, obtain consent), as well as post the updated Policy on this website noting the effective date of any changes.

### 13\. Business Transactions

We may assign or transfer this Policy, as well as information covered by this Policy, in the event of a merger, sale, change in control, or reorganization of all our part of our business.

### 14\. English Language Controls

Non-English translations of this Policy are provided for convenience only. In the event of any ambiguity or conflict between translations, the English version is authoritative and controls.

### 15\. Contact Information

**Registered Office**

**PushAlert (InkWired Technologies Private Limited)**  
C-101 Mahesh Nagar  
Tonk Phatak  
Jaipur – 302015  
Rajasthan (India)  
Attention: Data Protection Officer  

**Corporate Office**

**PushAlert (InkWired Technologies Private Limited)**  
#345 Vardhaman JP Plaza  
Sector-4, Dwarka  
New Delhi - 110075 (India)  
Attention: Data Protection Officer  

Last Updated: May 21, 2018

* * *

* * *

If you have any questions about these terms or anything else about the service, please reach out to us at:

or
